Some of you may not remember
when Conor McGregor knocked out José Aldo.
Now, for some of you
that aren't fight fans,
there's quite an important lesson in
this. Give me 30 seconds to cook.
McGregor, Aldo.
Aldo was really good. He
was a decorated long-term champion,
and there was a lot of shit beforehand,
and McGregor winded him up.
And the headline was
that Conor McGregor made $1.3 million per
second.
And I remember doing a marketing email
about this. But anyway, hold on.
Go.
Green trunks for the southpaw,
The Notorious Conor McGregor.
Black trunks for the champion,
José Aldo Jr.
Conor relaxed and smiling. Oh.
14 seconds. Champion. Now,
not to mention that he
predicted that he
was going to overstep with the right
and hit him with the left.
Forget that.
And irrespective of all of the shit
that Conor McGregor
has caused and goes through,
whether it's drug problems, alcohol,
whatever, this
was one of the most impressive feats ever.
But the issue is this, to insinuate
that he earned $1.3 million per second,
there's
a problem with this,
because this doesn't take into account all
of the work that
happened before.
And the reason I'm telling you about this
is from a comment,
"Feeling deflated after finding out you
made 7K for two and a half hours is
diabolical.
This is where I need to be."
But Mike here underneath comes in with a
clutch.
Two and a half hours of blabbing
is just the tip of the iceberg.
What required before
is the important part.
So zoom out for a sec.
I'm guilty of this as well,
flashing things like revenue.
And I'm going to do this right now as an
appeal to authority.
I just surpassed $5 million
in my business mentorship. Done
that in what? Two years.
Can make you feel a little bit shit.
You go, "5 million.
Wow, what I'd do with that."
But it's an appeal to authority.
The reason I'm saying this
is I need you to listen to what I say.
So it's like, I don't know,
if we did jujitsu
and you're being a bit mouthy, I'd
probably hit you with the fucking hip toss
to be like, "Oh, you ready to listen
now?" And I can even double down and go,
"Rah." Managed to make that
whilst also growing a nootropics business
to over $60
million valuation.
But I'm not saying this to make you feel
like shit.
I'm doing it as appeal to authority.
But the thing we really need to think
about is I'm 36.
So for a start,
I'm already a lot older than a lot of you.
Maybe not for everyone.
I got into the workforce at 16.
So it's 20 years. 20 years.
And I didn't start off being an
influencer.
There's a few lessons here I'm going to
teach you.
First of all, started working in a pub.
I worked in a pub called The Squirrels,
and it was off the back of a caravan site.
I used to get £5 an hour, and there
was a guy in there called Wayne, and I
always knew when it
was time for him to go home because he
always used to ask me,
"Do you like having your bum licked?" I
didn't know what that meant for fucking
another 10 years.
And then Wayne would pay me £50 a day to
be a laborer on the
building site.
So I would check my pub shifts, and
if I could do it, I would also
work laboring for him. And as a laborer,
you get the worst jobs.
So the things I'd do for £50 to then go
work in a pub for five.
Now, my boss was called Johnny
that worked in the pub, and he
was the first guy
that told me every person that comes in,
first time you meet them, shake their
hand. So when they're ordering drink,
shake their hand, say hello.
Look them in the eyes. And that
was something that
was kind of weird to me.
And he goes, "In time,
you'll remember their drinks order.
And when they come in, shout it to them.
Two John Smiths."
And it made people feel a little bit at
home, a little bit
welcome.
And I'll never forget being in trouble
with Johnny when I said, "Hey, I
want to have my birthday party at this
pub." He goes, "How old are you going to
be?" I said, "18." He was like,
"You prick.
You've been drinking here for like four
years." Went to uni, worked in bars at
festivals.
Remember Wireless Festival back in the
day?
And I used to be out the back carrying
crates to the bar.
Then I got my first job in a shopping
center selling LoveFilm, which was
where before Netflix, for some of you,
you used to have to get the DVDs and post
them back to each other. And that
was £7 for a sale, £9
if I got 10 sales in a day.
Shopping centers, people
that go up to you.
Stop you in your tracks. "Hey,
do you have a minute?" "No,
fuck off." "Cool." The
reason I'm telling you this
is it's very easy for you to potentially
get jealous
of my results,
but you're never going to be jealous of
the process of how I got
here. I've spoken about it before,
worked in door-to-door sales for NPower,
12K
base.
Then I went to work in pretty much a call
center,
where I'd be given an Excel spreadsheet of
people's phone numbers and names, and
they weren't expecting my call.
I once worked for a company called Log
Logic, and
their business, I wonder
if they're still going.
I used to bash phones for Log Logic.
This was it.
Security management, compliance reporting,
and IT operations.
Then, all right, I wonder if I put RSA.
Then I went in-house to RSA Security.
This right here was my office for nearly
two years.
Sales were on the third floor.
HR had the top floor.
I used to park my car around here to the
right.
I was on £20,000, and my commission
was capped at 5,000, which I thought was
a lot. Now here, again, I
was on the phones.
I was inside sales associate UK
and Ireland,
and we used to sell little tokens,
right?
And these little tokens used to come
and generate a code every minute
that you used to log in.
You know at the moment you've got the
authentication app.
That used to be a physical hardware
device, and we used to have them to
Lockheed Martin, Raytheon,
every big company had these security keys,
and I
used to sell them.
And I used to have to call up the
businesses and quantify the
size of the business. Then I quit here.
I went and played New Zealand in rugby for
six months, came back, worked in
recruitment for Eaton Bridge Partners.
Now they've deleted me.
I don't exist anymore. And I used to,
again, bash phones
for recruiting in finance. I
was a resourcer, so that in another
day. I was the recruiter's bitch,
in essence.
I used to have to create the shortlist
and call people up
and talk about it again.
I remember sitting there on Twitter,
and there were some guys I played rugby
with
at Windsor who were PTs,
and I looked at their tweets
and I thought, "Wow, imagine
that.
Imagine being a personal trainer as a
job." I was like, "That'd be amazing.
That'd be so good."
And then it got to a point where actually
I fell in love
with a girl, which was super annoying.
We moved to Asia for six months.
Then I got back, and I was so fat
and disgusted.
And imagine this, at 24,
I remember getting back from the airport
and
going for a run,
and I felt so disgusted with myself.
I was like,
"I'm going to become a PT because I want
to go to work in shorts." And
my dad always said to me, he was like,
"If you get a job you enjoy, you'll never
work a day in your life." I remember
that's probably the best advice he ever
gave
me. And I was like, do you know what?
30 pounds an hour.
If I could do three PT sessions a day,
that's 90 pounds a day. Laughing.
Now,
I went onto the gym floor with a lot of
experience
in marketing and in sales departments,
and I'm sure a lot of you have heard me
say
it before, that the first day at work,
I said, "Have you got an email list?
Have they opted in for marketing?
Do you mind if I email the list
and introduce
myself?" And they gave me the list,
and I sent the email out
and got my first like
12 to 15 clients from that. Again,
I didn't make it a sales list.
I didn't talk about PT.
I just introduced my name, said,
"If you want me to show
you anything,
it would benefit me because it would show
me on the gym floor, make
me look like I'm coaching people.
Take advantage of that." Anyway,
people will be
jealous of what you've achieved,
but not what you've had to do to get
there,
whether it was knocking on doors in
freezing cold or sitting in an office.
One year, by April,
I'd hit my commission for the year, my
5K. I said to my manager, Rachel, I go,
"I've hit my commission.
Can you get me more commission?" She said
no.
I said,
"What am I supposed to do between April
and December?" She goes, "Just hit
your 100 calls a day." So I used to call
Cornwall County Council.
Any of you that want to call Cornwall
County Council, you do so,
and it'll put you
on a loop where it'll go press one,
press two, press three, press four.
And when you get there,
I would pretty much just call them,
leave the phone off the hook for like an
hour.
Then at the end of the day, just bash,
bash, bash, bash, bash.
Then my average call time would be like a
minute, minute and a half.
And I did that from April to December.
And it sounds bad, but that
was devastating to me because I'm quite a
creative person. I do like working hard.
But I was given no incentive to do so.
When you start your own thing
and you work online,
you suddenly have an incentive
that the more I put out,
the more I get back.
And for me, it's a very exciting game,
and I'm very glad I got out of that.
Now, if you think 7K for two
and a half hours is good, I got paid
150,000 Australian dollars for a two-hour
talk last year.
So that's £75,000 for two hours. That
was crazy.
I felt so bad for them,
I went back the next year
and did it for free.
The point I'm trying to make
is any success that I have
is coming off the back
of 20 years of sales and marketing.
More recent of which, the reason
that I'm kind of not really a
PT anymore is because I did my last
personal training session in
2017, so nine years ago. I am so far
removed from being a coach,
and although my name online
was James Smith PT, all
I've been doing is sales and marketing.
All I've been doing
is writing marketing emails.
is creating landing pages.
So you think James Smith Academy,
three books, Neutonic,
business mentorship,
whatever it is.
I've got a very good touring business.
You think I just went on tour with Chris
Williamson, and he's doing all the venues
that I sold out two, three years ago.
The last seven years,
I have so many good campaigns that did
well, and when I say campaigns, I mean,
right,
we're doing a three-month challenge.
Let's call it this.
Let's package it like this.
Let's charge this. Boom.
So many of them bombed.
So many of them I thought would do well.
Other times they did well,
sometimes better, sometimes worse.
I've created nearly 5,000 Instagram posts.
So sometimes I think I'm guilty, 4,939.
But then again, right,
that's on my main page.
I've got four Instagrams,
James Smith Academy, 100,000.
The Problem With podcasts, 50,000.
James Smith Business, nearly 50,000.
When you hire me now in my mentorship,
you are not buying anything apart
from all the experience
that got me to the position I'm in.
And although I'm guilty of flashing things
like revenue here, even though my net
revenue is like 4753, so where's
that 250 gone?
I don't have it. This
is the result of 20 years of work
and seven years
of digital marketing,
and that's what you get when you hire me.
I've had so many posts bomb, so many
that I thought were going to go well,
so many
ideas that have just fallen on dead ends.
Now, after I-- wow, okay,
that's interesting.
After I finish this call,
I am going into the Discord here, and
I'm going to be helping people. This
is what I do day to day.
This is how I've made the five mil,
the 4750.
And every piece of content that I curate,
every landing page that I look
at.
I'm going to show you something quickly as
well.
You are paying for the years of work I
have done.
You might not be able to see this,
but this thing here will show you there's
over
100,000 messages
that have gone through the Discord,
and 36% of
them, one in three, are from me.
And the response rate is 89%.
So I want to formally apologize for
throwing numbers in your face
that can make you
feel bad, but the numbers
are an accumulation of years and years
and years of
work. So there's two lessons for you.
One, for many of you,
you've only been doing this three, four,
five years.
It's not a massive amount of time to get
good at these skills.
I've been training jujitsu nine years,
nearly full time, still got tapped
out today. The second thing is,
if you choose to hire me through my
business
mentorship, that's what you're buying.
And it sounds weird, right?
Not just running a fitness app,
you're also buying the time I had in
recruitment.
You're buying the marketing
and sales stuff that I learned from a
company called
Clarify in Thiel,
which I did for three months.
And I'll say this again because we're
about to do a price hike. Fuck it.
Going to put my email address in the
description just beneath the offer.
If you join today and in the next two,
three months, you do what I tell you to
and you don't see a meaningful return on
the investment that you pay me, just email
me and we'll hash it out.
That doesn't mean you go, "James, sorry,
I haven't done
anything with it.
Can I get my money back?" I don't think
that's fair.
But if you go, "Look, I did this,
I did this, I did this,
and it's not worked."
Well,
hopefully by now you should know I'm not
just a money-hungry bastard.
So that divided by the amount of hours
that I've worked, it's a lot more
reasonable. Anyway, hope you enjoyed that.
Check out the offer.
Hope you enjoyed a little story time.
If not, click this video here
and it'll take you to a new video.